Guide to the Alfred E. Heller Collection of World's Fair Material
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Printed Material, 1864-2005; Series III; (25 boxes)
  - New York Exhibition of the Industry of All Nations (1853-1854) (Box 23)
  - Exposition universelle de 1855 (Paris, France) (Box 23)
  - American Exhibition (1887: London, England) (Box 23)
  - World's Columbian Exposition (1893: Chicago, Illinois), 1892; 1928; 2 (Box 23)
  - California Midwinter International Exposition (1894: San Francisco, California) (Box 23)
  - Trans-Mississippi and International Exposition (1898: Omaha, Nebraska) (Box 23)
  - Exposition universelle internationale de 1900 (Paris, France) (Box 23)
  - Louisiana Purchase Exposition (1904: St. Louis, Missouri), 2 (Box 23)
  - Exposition internationale de Lyon (1914: Lyon, France) (Box 23)
  - Panama-California Exposition (1915: San Diego, California) (Box 23)
  - Panama-Pacific International Exposition (1915: San Francisco, California), 1976-1982; 2 (Box 23)
  - The Philippine Carnival of Manila (1916: Manila, Philippines) (Box 23)
  - Cotton Palace Exposition (1917: Waco, Texas) (Box 23)
  - Exposição do Centenario do Brasil (1922-1923: Rio de Janeiro, Brazil) (Box 23)
  - Exposición Ibero-Americana (1929-1930: Seville, Spain) (Box 23)
  - Century of Progress International Exposition (1933-1934: Chicago, Illinois), 3 (Box 23)
  - California Pacific International Exposition (1935-1936: San Diego, California), 2 (Box 23)
  - Great Lakes Exposition (1937: Cleveland, Ohio) (Box 23)
  - New York World's Fair (1939-1940), 1939; 1989-1990; 6 (Box 23)
  - Golden Gate International Exposition (1939-1940: San Francisco, California), 1939-1940, 1988; 16 (Box 23)
  - Festival of Britain (1951: London, England) (Box 23)
  - Century 21 Exposition (1962: Seattle, Washington), 2 (Box 23)
  - New York World's Fair (1964-1965), 7 (Box 23)
  - Expo '67 (Montreal, Quebec), 1967; 4 (Box 23)
  - Expo '74 (Spokane, Washington), 1974; 5 (Box 23)
  - Expo '75 (1975: Okinawa, Japan), 2 (Box 23)
  - Various Japanese Fairs and Expositions, 1981-1995; 18 (Box 24)
    Includes material relating to fairs and expositions held in Kobe Port Island, Fukuoka, Nagoya, Sendai, Hiroshima, Yokohama, Osaka, Nagasaki, Iwate, Kobe, Wakayama, Mie, and Okayama.
  - World's Fair of 1982 (1982: Knoxville, Tennessee), 7 (Box 24)
  - World's Fair of 1982 (1982: Knoxville, Tennessee), 17 (Box 25)
  - Lousiana World Exposition (1984: New Orleans, Louisiana), 3 (Box 25)
  - Lousiana World Exposition (1984: New Orleans, Louisiana), 105 (Box 26)
  - Lousiana World Exposition (1984: New Orleans, Louisiana), 41 (Box 27)
  - Lousiana World Exposition (1984: New Orleans, Louisiana), 23 (Box 28)
  - Lousiana World Exposition (1984: New Orleans, Louisiana), 1981-1985; 46 (Box 29)
  - Expo '85 (1985: Tsukuba, Japan), 16 (Box 29)
  - Expo '85 (1985: Tsukuba, Japan), 55 (Box 30)
  - Expo 86 (1986: Vancouver, British Columbia), 1986-1992; 42 (Box 30)
  - Expo 86 (1986: Vancouver, British Columbia), 93 (Box 31)
  - Expo 86 (1986: Vancouver, British Columbia), 30 (Box 32)
  - Expo '88 (1986: Brisbane, Queensland), 1988; 36 (Box 32)
  - Expo '88 (1986: Brisbane, Queensland), 1988; 39 (Box 33)
  - International Specialized Exhibition "Christopher Columbus, Ships and the Sea" (1992: Genoa, Italy), 37 (Box 34)
  - Exposición Universal de 1992 (1992: Seville, Spain), 26 (Box 34)
  - Exposición Universal de 1992 (1992: Seville, Spain), 78 (Box 35)
  - Exposición Universal de 1992 (1992: Seville, Spain), 56 (Box 36)
  - Expo '93 (1993: Taejon, Korea), 14 (Box 36)
  - Expo '93 (1993: Taejon, Korea), 99 (Box 37)
  - Expo '93 (1993: Taejon, Korea), 22 (Box 38)
  - Expo '93 (1993: Taejon, Korea), 18 (Box 39)
  - Expo '98 (1998: Lisbon, Portugal), 85 (Box 40)
  - Expo '98 (1998: Lisbon, Portugal), 3 (Box 41 Oversize)
  - Expo '98 (1998: Lisbon, Portugal), 75 (Box 42)
  - Expo 2000 (2000: Hannover, Germany), 29 (Box 43)
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Copies of electronic files are available through Access Services: Disk #1, "Frie Expo 2000 - Hanorarfreier Abdruck für redaktionelle Beiträge."
  - Millennium Dome (2000: London, United Kingdom) (Box 43)
  - World Exposition-Aichi (2005) (Box 43)
  - Various, 1864-2005
    Includes material relating to various fairs, including unofficial ones and planned ones that did not take place.
    - World Fairs and Expositions General (financing, press cuttings, design, etc.), 1986-1993 (Box 43)
    - World Fairs and Expositions, USA and Canada, 1864-1902 (Box 43)
    - World Fairs and Expositions, Europe, 1981 (Box 43)
    - Manila, Philippines (Did not take place), 2002; 3 (Box 43)
    - Otawa / Hull, Canada (Did not take place), 2005 (Box 43)
    - Chicago, IL (Did not take place), 1992 (Box 43)
    - Vienna-Budapest (cancelled - did not take place), 1996 (Box 43)
    - Tokyo Urban Frontier (cancelled - did not take place), 1996 (Box 44)
    - Stockholm, 1997 (Box 44)
    - Seine-Saint Denis, Paris (Did not take place), 2004 (Box 44)
    - Amsterdam - Floriade, 1982 (Box 44)
    - Alaska (Did not take place), 1984 (Box 44)
    - Eiffel (Box 44)
    - Osaka EXPO, 1990 (Box 44)
    - London, 1978 (Box 44)
    - Hiroshima, Asian Games, 1994 (Box 44)
    - Sacramento, 1940 (Box 44)
    - Stockholm, 1997 (Box 44)
    - Triennale di Milano, 1987-1998 (Box 44)
    - Liverpool, International Garden Festival, 1984 (Box 44)
    - Munich, International Garden Festival, 1983 (Box 44)
    - Budapest (Box 44)
    - Portland, Oregon, 1905 (Box 44)
    - Hiroshima, Japan (Box 44)
    - Floriade, 1992 (Box 44)
    - 1992 1992 1992 (Box 44)
    - Expo, 1990 (Box 44)
    - 1996 1996 1996 (Box 44)
    - Crystal Palace Commemoration, 1986 (Box 44)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 44)
    - 1959 1959 1959 (Box 44)
    - San Francisco Bibliography (Box 44)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 44)
  - Miscellaneous, 1939-1992; 6 (Box 45 Oversize)
    "Souvenir views of the New York World's Fair" (circa 1939)
    Life Magazine, New York World's Fair, (1 May 1964)
    Life Magazine, Montreal Expo 67 (28 April 1967)
    Ferris Wheel drawing (circa 1980)
    Discover It, Seville 1992
    A Technological Development Project in Andalusia, Seville 1992 (circa 1989)
  - The Courier-Mail: Expo Week, 1988 April-September (Box 46 Oversize)
  - Unsorted material, 1939-1993; 18 (Box 48)
    Includes postcards, postage stamps, and printed ephemera.
- Restricted Fragile Material
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Computer disk (Box 47)